# Taizhou Chen (陳泰舟)

(+86)15889283632 | ivonchan0414@outlook.com | http://sweb.cityu.edu.hk/taizhchen2

#### About me

I am a PhD candidate from School of Creative Media, City University of Hong Kong, under supervised by Dr. Kening Zhu and Prof. Hongbo Fu. My research interest lies in the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction and applied machine learning, in which I am currently focusing on investigating sensing technologies, leveraging deep learning algorithm. I also have researches experiences on VR/AR haptic feedback, tangible interface design, smart wearable devices, and multi-modal interface design. I have publications on top conference such as CHI and IEEE VR, and top journal such as IJHCS and TVCG.

HongKong, China

#### EDUCATION

City University of Hong Kong

PhD in Creative Media, Supervisor: Dr. Kening Zhu, Co-supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu	$Sept. \ 2018-Now$
City University of Hong Kong MA in Creative Media, GPA: 3.81/4.0, with Distinction	HongKong, China Sept. 2016 – Oct. 2017
Experience	
Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd. Research Engineer Intern	Shenzhen, China Oct. 2020 – Apr.2021
Tsinghua University Visiting Student	Beijing, China Dec. 2019 – Apr. 2020
City University of Hong Kong Research Assistant	HongKong, China Jan. 2017 – Aug. 2018

## Р

TVCG /

2020

**IEEE VR 2021** 

CHI Symposium

Publications			
Upcoming	<b>Taizhou Chen</b> , Tianpei Li, Xingyu Yang, Kening Zhu. EFRing: Enabling Thumbto-Index-Finger Microgesture Interaction through Electric Field Sensing using Single Smart Ring		
MTA	Taizhou Chen, Kening Zhu, Ming Chieh Yang. PickSense: Deep-Learning-based Unobtrusive Handedness Prediction for One-handed Smartphone InteractionDeep-learning-based unobtrusive handedness prediction for one-handed smartphone interaction. Multimed Tools Appl (2022). ISSN: 1573-7721 https://doi.org/10.1007/s11042-021-11844-6		
IJHCS	Taizhou Chen, Lantian Xu, Kening Zhu. FritzBot: A Data-Driven Con-		

versational Agent for Physical-Computing System Design, in International Journal of Human-Computer Studies, Volume 155, November 2021, ISSN: 1071-5819 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2021.102699

Taizhou Chen, Lantian Xu, Xianshan Xu and Kening Zhu, GestOnHMD: Enabling Gesture-based Interaction on Low-cost VR Head-Mounted Display, in IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, ISSN: 1941-0506, doi: 10.1109/TVCG.2021.3067689.

Zhiyi Rong, Ngo Fung Chan, **Taizhou Chen**, Kening Zhu. CodeRhythm: A Tangible Programming Toolkit for Visually Impaired Students. In Proceedings of Asian CHI Symposium 2020, ACM CHI 2020. Best Paper Award.

HCII 2020

Arshad Nasser, **Taizhou Chen**, Can Liu, Kening Zhu, P. V. M. Rao. 2020. FingerTalkie: Designing A Low-cost Finger-worn Device for Interactive Audio Labeling of Tactile Diagrams. In Proceedings of International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction (HCI International) 2020. Springer, Cham.

**HCII 2020** 

Zhiyi Rong, Ngo Fung Chan, **Taizhou Chen**, Kening Zhu. Toward Inclusive Learning: Designing and Evaluating Tangible Programming Blocks for Visually Impaired Students. In Proceedings of International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction (HCI International) 2020. Springer, Cham.

INTERACT 2019

**Taizhou Chen**, Yi-Shiun Wu, and Kening Zhu. DupRobo: Interactive Robotic Autocompletion of Physical Block-based Repetitive Structure. In Proceedings of the 17th IFIP TC.13 International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction (INTERACT 2019). Springer-Verlag, Berlin, Heidelberg, 19 pages.

**IJHCS** 

Kening Zhu, Simon Perrault, **Taizhou Chen**, Shaoyu Cai, Roshan Lalintha Peiris. A sense of ice and fire: Exploring thermal feedback with multiple thermoelectric-cooling elements on a smart ring. International Journal of Human-Computer Studies. Volume 130, 2019, Pages 234-247, ISSN 1071-5819, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2019.07.003.

CHI 2019

Kening Zhu, **Taizhou Chen**, Feng Han, and Yi-Shiun Wu. 2019. HapTwist: Creating Interactive Haptic Proxies in Virtual Reality Using Low-cost Twistable Artefacts. In CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Proceedings (CHI 2019), May 4–9, 2019, Glasgow, Scotland UK. ACM, New York, NY, USA, 13 pages. https://doi.org/10.1145/3290605.3300923.

VRST 2018

Taizhou Chen, Yi-Shiun Wu, and Kening Zhu. 2018. Investigating Different Modalities of Directional Cues for Multi-task Visual-Searching Scenario in Virtual Reality. In VRST 2018: 24th ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology (VRST '18), November 28 - December 1, 2018, Tokyo, Japan. ACM, New York, NY, USA, 6 pages. Acceptance Rate: 22%.

#### Extended Abstracts

CHI 2020

Taizhou Chen. 2020. Facilitating Physical-Computer System Design through Data-Driven Natural-Language Interaction. In Extended Abstracts of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI EA '20). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 1–6.DOI:https://doi.org/10.1145/3334480.3381442.

SIGGRAPH Asia 2018 Kening Zhu, **Taizhou Chen**, Shaoyu Cai, Feng Han, and Yi-Shiun Wu. 2018. Demo - HapTwist: Creating Interactive Haptic Proxies in Virtual Reality Using Low-cost Twistable Artefacts. In Proceedings of SA '18 Virtual and Augmented Reality . ACM, New York, NY, USA, 2 pages.

SIGGRAPH Asia 2017 **Taizhou Chen**, Yi-Shiun Wu, Feng Han, Baochuan Yue, and Kening Zhu. 2017. DupRobo: an interactive robotic platform for physical block-based autocompletion. In SIGGRAPH Asia 2017 Posters (SA '17). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 19, 1–2. DOI:https://doi.org/10.1145/3145690.3145708.

SIGGRAPH Asia 2017

**Taizhou Chen**, Junyu Liu, Kening Zhu, and Tamas Waliczky. 2017. The golden guardian: multi-sensory immersive gaming through multi-sensory spatial cues. In SIGGRAPH Asia 2017 VR Showcase (SA '17). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Article 12, 2 pages. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/3139468.3139473. Acceptance rate: 25%.

Р	Δ٦	ГE	NΠ	ГS

2020

Kening Zhu, Feng Han, **Taizhou chen**, Yi-Shiun Wu, Systems and methods for creating haptic proxies for use in virtual reality. Patent No. US20200341538A1. Publication date: 29 Oct 2020.

## AWARD

## The Outstanding Academic Performance Award for Research Degree Students

2021

Academic year 2020 - 21, City University of Hong Kong

## Research Tuition Scholarship

2020

Academic year 2020 - 21, City University of Hong Kong

## The Outstanding Academic Performance Award for Research Degree Students

2019

Academic year 2018 - 19, City University of Hong Kong

## ACADEMIC SERVICES

## PC Member

IEEE AIVR 2020/2021

## Reviewer

CHI 2019/2020/2021, SIGGRAPH 2022, SIGGRAPH Asia 2018/2020/2021, IEEE VR 2020/2021, MobileCHI 2020, ICMI 2020/2021, ISS 2020/2021, IUI 2020/2021/2022, SUI 2020, ISWC 2018

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## Teaching Assistant

SM1103A Introduction to Media Computing

2018/19 Semester A

2019/20 Semester A

## Lecturer

CS4187 Computer Vision for Interactivity

2018/19 Semester A

2019/20 Semester A

2020/21 Semester A

2022/03/10 updated